Matt Bennett

Greater Atlanta area, Georgia | (678) 360-3651 | mbennett21484@gmail.com

Qualifications Summary

Full stack coding bootcamp graduate. Specializes in JavaScript, NodeJS, Express JS, Mysql, and React. Professional strengths include written and verbal communication, time management, and problem-solving. Detail-oriented professional with 3+ years in web performance, cybersecurity, and voice over IP sales.

Professional Experience

GEORGIA TECH FULL STACK IMMERSIVE CODING BOOTCAMP

Completed May, 2021

 Developed front end and full stack applications using JavaScript and multiple libraries and frameworks

Notable projects:

- Created dog breed matcher using 3rd party APIs to help users find breeds that match their lifestyle and displayed adoptable dogs of compatible breeds located at nearby shelters
- Built a property management CRM for landlords to keep track of their properties, tenants, and leases using MySQL database, Handlebars, and deployed to Heroku

AKAMAI TECHNOLOGIES, ATLANTA, GA

Sales Development Representative, Aug 2018 - Feb, 2021

- Developed and nurtured relationships with executive level stakeholders to generate revenue and consistently meet and exceed quota
- Uncover business needs of and apply solution knowledge to attain new customers
- Coordinated sales activities with consultants, solutions engineers, channel partners to identify and close new business
- Consistently attained and exceeded monthly and quarterly quotas

VONAGE BUSINESS, ATLANTA, GA

Account Executive, Nov 2017 - Aug 2018

- Provided customized VoIP phone solutions for small to mid-market sized businesses
- Worked with customers nationwide in a variety of fields such as ecommerce, finance, technology, legal, insurance and healthcare
- Proactively managed internal resources to ensure best outcome for existing and potential customers
- Used a consultative approach for customers that were often unfamiliar with VoIP technology and its benefits virtual receptionists, call groups, call recording, CRM integration, etc.
- Consistently achieved and exceeded quarterly sales quotas

VONAGE BUSINESS, ATLANTA, GA

Sales Development Representative, Jul 2017 – Nov 2017

- Qualified sales opportunities while meeting above average standards of customer service
- Met and exceeded daily activity expectations and opportunity generation
- Rapidly promoted from qualifying prospects to closing business and driving revenue

RAY'S ON THE RIVER, ATLANTA, GA

Shift Leader/Banquet Leader, Apr 2016 – Jun 2017

• Studied fine wine and cuisine to drive sales

- Earned position on banquet team and trusted as banquet leader to head major events and execute quality service
- Promoted to Shift Leader which comprised of opening and closing restaurant duties and training new hires

THE MILL KITCHEN AND BAR, ROSWELL, GA

Server/Bar Tender/Trainer, Mar 2013 – Apr 2016

- Trained majority of service staff on company procedures, standards of excellence and suggestive selling
- Created front-of-house side work charts and procedures for management to implement throughout the restaurant
- Provided exceptional guest experiences and customer service

Education

LASSITER HIGH SCHOOL, MARIETTA, GA

High School Diploma, May 2002

References

References available upon request